Johnnie Gonzalez

Elizabeth, New Jersey 07208 | 862-220-1841 | johnnie.agonz71@gmail.com | Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React and Redux based programming and a background in architectural design. Strong skills in team work, time management, problem solving, and self learning. Striving to help lead in innovative design and green technology with a passion for all that is sustainable.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby | Rails | Active Record | JavaScript | React | Redux | CSS | HTML | Photoshop | PostgreSQL | SQL | SQL | SQLite | Version control | Debugging | Testing

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

09/2020 - 12/2020

i dii Stack web Developilietit, ixuby on ixalis and JavaScript program

Union County CollegeAssociate of Science - AS, Architecture/Engineering

Cranford, NJ
01/2016- 12/2018

Societies - Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society GPA: 3.7

GPA: 3.7

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Eco Share - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

Created an interactive social media application where creatives can come together and share their eco-friendly designs.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails, Active Record in backend; JavaScript, React.js, Redux.js in the frontend.
- Implemented Ruby's serializer gem to access related data decreasing production time.
- Managed to implement a stretch goal of having a user design feed by creating a "follow" feature.

Ez Task - Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

Created a clean and simple single-page application where users can view/create tasks and delete accordingly.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails, Active Record in backend. Vanilla JavaScript in the frontend.
- Create, Edit, Delete tasks rendering to the DOM without a page refresh.
- Task visibility for walk-by security. Enabling users to hide tasks at the click of a button.

Avatar - Github | Video Demo

Created a fun Interactive Ruby CLI game that users can explore the world of Pandora.

- Utilized **Ruby on Rails**, and Active Record to access a relational Sqlite3 Database.
- Implemented TTY Prompt so users can pick a path to explore.
- User stats affected Set up incrementing and decrementing stats to database Depending on the path stats can be affected (health, food...etc..)
- Debugged a significant problem within hours before presentation.

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Architecture

Verona, New Jersey 09/2019 - 03/2020

Architectural Intern

- Created blueprints and 3D floor plans based on client specifications, suggested changes as needed
- Performed detailed measurements at client site and applied to the schematics
- Worked with vendors to ensure timely delivery of orders to meet project deadlines and win bids

 OTG
 Newark, New Jersey

 Server
 02/2016 - 03/2020

- Ensured customer satisfaction at high volume airport bar, working with a variety of clientele
- Performed a myriad of tasks as needed to keep multiple restaurants efficiently running
- Stocked inventory, estimated needs, replenished orders; opened and closed restaurant